"sekkaku hareta kara" tte iiwake o hitotsu houri nage
"The sun's finally out", I shout out an excuse
gareeji kara ikioi makase tobidashita
and fly out of the garage eagerly
mokutekichi wa minami e
I head south, pedaling hard toward the ocean
fumikonde iku pedaru wa umi no hou
chizu nante minai kimerareta you na ruuto wa iya
I don't want to take a route that
I already know without looking at a map
dareka no wadachi wa ashi ga torarete komaru
Following someone else's well-worn path
will only slow me down
isshinfuran ni egaku icchokusen rain wa
The straight line drawn with my heart and soul
boku ni shika mirenai panorama e tsuzuku
continues on toward a panorama that only I can see
konma ni-byou no mirai e ima o kirihiraite ike!
Unlock the present into a 0.2 second future!
tonikaku koge
Pedal until the end
Itachi's Story – Light and Darkness:
The Darkness of the Akatsuki
Do you know a shinobi
named Might Dai?
I know a Might Guy.
Huh, well that’s the kid from that time.
I was one of the Seven Ninja
Swordsmen of the Mist.
(十蔵)マイト・ダイっていう
忍を知ってるか？
(イタチ)マイト・ガイなら知っているが。
Thanks to Might Dai,
the seven of us got cut down to three.
あぁ… そりゃ
あんときのガキのほうだな。
俺は 霧隠れ忍刀七人衆の
１人だったが→
Who could have expected that
scuzzy bearded jerk
マイト・ダイのおかげで→
would use taijutsu like that?
あんときの七人衆は
三人衆にされちまったんだよ。
Anyway, I wanna make
something clear...
あんな むさ髭野郎が
あんな体術を使うなんて→
I could care less why
you joined the Akatsuki.
誰が思うかよ。
I don’t even want
to hear your reason.
だから はっきりしておかなきゃ
ならねえことがある。
It doesn’t matter why I joined either.
お前が なんで
暁に入ったかなんてのは→
And it’s okay if
you don’t want to know.
どうでもいいことだ。
別に聞きたくもない。
Listen to me!
俺が なんで暁に入ったなんてのも
どうでもいいことだ。
聞きたくなければ それでもいい。
There’s something
I need to ask you.
(十蔵)聞けよ！
And...
It’s about your ninjutsu specialties.
いいか？ お前に聞いておかなきゃ
ならないことがある。
As you see, I use this Executioner’s Blade
and cut up enemies.
それは お前の得意忍術だ。
So? How about you?
Genjutsu, Fire Style and Shuriken Jutsu.
見てのとおり
俺は この首切り包丁で→
You’re awfully humble!
Former ANBU Itachi Uchiha, Itachi of
the Sharingan, the Clan-Killer Itachi...
敵に切り込んでいく。
で お前は？
(イタチ)幻術 火遁 手裏剣術。
People throw around many nicknames
for you... you’re notorious.
ずいぶんと控えめな野郎だな。
元木ノ葉の暗部 うちはイタチ。
Let’s decide on our formations.
写輪眼のイタチ 一族殺しのイタチの名は
あっちこっちに響いてるぜ。
You’ll start with a preemptive attack
with your genjutsu, shuriken or
whatever’s your specialty.
Then I’ll jump in.
俺らのフォーメーションを決めておく。
And you back me up.
まず お前が幻術でも手裏剣でも
なんでもいいから→
That will be Formation B
得意の術で先制攻撃をしろ。
What’s A?
We each do things our own way.
そして 俺が突っ込む。
Understood.
お前は 後方から援護に入る。
One word of warning.
それが フォーメーションＢ。
Don’t take any opponent for granted.
(イタチ)Ａは？
別々に好きにやる… だ。
Understood.
了解した。
ひとつ忠告しておくぜ。
相手を
見た目で 甘く見るんじゃねえぞ。
了解。
- Who are you?
- Get out of our way!
Shinobi villages only say things
about peace and order,
but they’re really worried
about their roles shrinking.
Behind the scenes,
they’re all trying
なにヤツ！
そこをどけ！
忍の里は平和だ安定だ
なんて言いながら→
to lessen their opponent’s power
while increasing their own.
All the while, preventing other nations
from finding out their schemes.
その役割が小さくなることを
心配する。
水面下では
どこも相手の勢力を削ぎ→
That’s why the Akatsuki gets jobs.
The more peaceful the world is,
the more work we get...
自分の勢力を増やそうと考える。
ただし その軍事行動が
他国にバレないようにだ。
We accept every request.
We don’t care about the details.
だから 暁に仕事が来る。
You scoundrels!
世の中が平和なら平和なほどな。
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu!
依頼があれば 何でも受ける。
内容なんか知ったこっちゃねえ。
おのれ 曲者！
Why you—!
火遁 豪火球の術！
ぐあっ！
わ～！
That’s why...
この！
We don’t know who’s inside
this palanquin...
And we don’t want to know either.
だから
駕籠の中身が誰かも知らない。
知る必要もない。
There’s also no need to think about
who the hell would pay us
to do such dirty work.
だから こんな嫌がらせみたいな
仕事でも→
誰が何のために
依頼してきたかなんて→
That’s what the Akatsuki is about.
考える必要もない。
Pain, the leader, said the Akatsuki
was going to rule the world.
That won’t be for a long time.
それが 暁だ。
We first need to amass money
and power.
リーダーのペインは→
暁が世界を支配すると
言っていたが。
Speak of the devil,
he’s summoning us.
そりゃ まだまだ先の話だ。
まず 金と力を蓄えるんだとよ。
言ってるそばから お呼びだ。
So Itachi, have you gotten
used to the Akatsuki?
How would you feel about changing
partners and teaming up with me?
Hey, we’re just getting
our formation down.
(大蛇丸)どう イタチ君
暁には慣れた？
なんなら パートナーを
替えてもらうのは どう？
Don’t try to steal him.
I second changing partners...
私と ツーマンセルというのは？
(十蔵)おいおい ようやく
フォーメーションが固まってきたんだ。
There’s an aspect called compatibility...
I wish our leader would put
a bit more thought into this.
引き抜きは なしだぜ。
(ヒルコ)パートナーを替えるっていうのは
俺も賛成だ。
You’re one to talk, you damn snake!
相性ってもんがある。
リーダーも もう少し
考えてほしいところね。
(ヒルコ)お前が言うな 蛇野郎！ チッ！
Thanks to your work, Akatsuki’s reputation
is growing in the underworld.
The jobs we’re getting are
becoming bigger in scale,
which means higher compensation
as well.
(ペイン)お前たちの働きによって
暁の名も裏世界で広まってきた。
But that’s only just a step.
And the Akatsuki is ready to
move on to the next step...
依頼される仕事の
規模も大きくなり→
それに見合った
報酬も手にできる。
which are the Tailed Beasts.
だが それは手段に過ぎない。
暁は次の段階に入る。
There’re supposed to be nine of ‘em.
Are those the Tailed Beasts?
The Five Great Ninja Nations
harbor most of them.
But the whereabouts are unknown
for a few of them.
次は尾獣だ。
(十蔵)尾獣って
９匹いるっていう あれか？
Those who aren’t on a job
will try to locate them.
(ペイン)その多くは
忍五大国が抱えているが→
So we just have to locate them?
For now.
どこにいるのか
判明していない尾獣がいる。
What will you do with them eventually?
We’ll hunt down and collect
every Tailed Beast.
手の空いた者は
その所在を調査しろ。
And then?
(角都)調査だけでいいのか？
(ペイン)今は まだな。
They’ll act as our deterrents in our quest
for world domination.
(大蛇丸)ゆくゆくは どうするの？
Tailed Beasts?
(ペイン)尾獣すべてを狩り集める。
(大蛇丸)それで？
Seems to me there are
lots of other ways...
それが 世界征服のための
抑止力となる。
There’s no mistake in
the leader’s reasoning.
(大蛇丸)尾獣ねぇ 他の手段が
いくらでもあると思うけど。
Here are the assignments.
Juzo...
You’ll handle the request
from the Land of Water.
(ゼツ)リーダーの考えに間違いはない。
Isn’t there another mission I can do?!
任務を割り振る。
You’re familiar with the territory.
十蔵 お前たちは
水の国からの依頼だ。
ウヘッ 別の任務は ねえのかよ？
(ペイン)お前なら
土地勘があるだろう。
This is ridiculous.
I never wanted to go back
to that depressing place.
(十蔵)チッ！
Is that the village where you’re from?
The job’s easy.
ムチャ振りしやがる。
あんな辛気臭ぇとこ 二度と
行きたくなかったんだがな。
We have to assassinate a member
from the Feudal Lord's clan
in the Land of Water.
(イタチ)アンタの元里か。
I'll explain...
It’s an intra-clan fight
over succession,
(十蔵)仕事としては単純だ。
a common occurrence in
the Land of Water.
水の国の大名家の
とある人物を暗殺する。
The Hidden Mist cannot interfere
in the Feudal Clan's affairs.
解説してやるが→
That’s why they’ve come to the Akatsuki.
これは 水の国でよくある
お家騒動 お跡目争いだ。
大名家に対して
霧隠れの里は介入できない。
This river’s the border.
だから 暁に依頼が来た。
Have you ever been to
the Land of Water?
Never on a mission.
So for an outing then?
(十蔵)この河が国境だが
水の国に来たことはあるか？
You’ve got no sense of humor!
But you do know, don’t you?
(イタチ)任務ではない。
What happens to a shinobi
from another village
遠足か？
if he’s discovered in
the Land of Water?
ノリの悪い野郎だな。
The Hidden Mist doesn’t have
a policy for prisoner exchange...
だが 水の国の領地で→
If captured, the shinobi will be made
to divulge his jutsu
他里の忍が発見されたら
どうなるかは知ってるな？
and he’ll be disposed of.
You have it good, Itachi.
霧隠れは捕虜交換に応じない。
The Leaf is naïve.
捕まった忍は その術を→
That’s why you and Orochimaru can go
around without a care as Rogue Ninja...
徹底的に暴かれたうえに消される。
There is a special unit in the Hidden Mist
that track down Rogue Ninja.
お前は まだいいぜ イタチ。
木ノ葉は ぬるい。
If I ever get caught in this village...
お前や大蛇丸が のうのうと
抜け忍やってられるんだからな。
Oh, I forgot all about Formation C.
霧隠れには 追い忍っていう
抜け忍狩り専門の部隊がある。
If I’m caught by the Mist,
kill me immediately.
俺が この里で捕らえられたら…。
あ～ フォーメーションＣを忘れてたぜ。
If I have a chance.
So what do you want me
to do for Formation D?
もし俺が霧隠れに捕まったら
お前の手で さっさと殺してくれ。
Nothing in particular.
余裕があれば。
Fine, let’s get going!
フォーメーションＤのときは
どうしてほしい？
特に希望はない。
んじゃ 行くか。
Are you good at infiltrating?
I'm average.
Okay, show me.
お前 忍び込むってのは
うまいほうか？
普通だ。
んじゃ それを見せてもらおうか。
P-Please! Spare me!
I don’t bear a grudge against you.
This is just my job.
W-Wait!
た 頼む 命だけは…。
(十蔵)
アンタに恨みがあるわけじゃない。
Hey...
ただ 仕事なんでな。
Yeah.
Hidden Mist Jutsu...!
ま 待ってくれ！
Wind Style! Supreme Typhoon!
おい。
あぁ。
This is—?!
霧隠れの術。
(やぐら)風遁 台風一過！
Lord Fourth!
こいつは…。
Is that the Mizukage?
Do you remember my warning?
Any way you look at him,
he’s a kid.
四代目。
He’s the Jinchuriki of
the Three Tails.
水影か。
俺の忠告を覚えてるか？
And they are the Mist’s
Shinobi Tracking Unit.
I never expected you to reappear
in the Village, Juzo.
(イタチ)どう見ても子供だな。
あれで 三尾の人柱力だ。
I didn’t wanna come back either.
I had no choice.
んで これが霧隠れの追い忍。
I have a ton of things to say to you...
(やぐら)まさか お前がこの里に→
At the very least, I’m taking back
the Executioner’s Blade.
再び現れるとは思わなかったぞ
十蔵。
俺だって来たかなかったんだが
しようがねえ。
Even if your partner
is Itachi of the Sharingan.
お前に言いたいことは
海ほどあるが→
So I guess a surprise attack with
your genjutsu is meaningless.
少なくとも その首切り包丁は
里に返してもらう。
お前のその仲間が
写輪眼のイタチであろうともな。
What do you want to do?
This one’s a Formation C.
あ～ となると不意打ちで
お前の幻術ってわけにも→
Formation C? Understood.
ちょっと いかねえな。
どうする？
フォーメーションＣだな こりゃ。
Don’t look!
フォーメーションＣか 了解した。
It's a Water Clone!
Itachi!
見るな！
Fire Style: Fireball Jutsu.
Lord Fourth!
水分身!?
(十蔵)イタチ！
火遁 豪火球の術！
あっ！
四代目！
You two...
ヘッ。
I’ll show no mercy.
お前たち 容赦しないぞ！
Tailed Beast State?!
The Fourth is a Jinchuriki
who can control his Tailed Beast!
This is not the Hidden Leaf!
尾獣化!?
四代目は 尾獣のコントロールができる
人柱力だ。
木ノ葉と一緒にすんじゃねえぞ！
Juzo!
It’s the Fourth’s Coral Palm Jutsu.
十蔵！
四代目の珊瑚掌の術だ！
Juzo?!
うお～！
Run... Itachi...
十蔵！
ぐほ…。
逃げろ イタチ…。
W-What?!
What is this?
The power of the Mangekyo Sharingan?
なんだ？
これは…。
あぁ うあ～!!
万華鏡写輪眼の力!?
Why you—!
うっ…。
こっ この…。
Juzo...?
Did you kill... the Mizukage?
十蔵。
No, he’s not dead yet.
Then...
Hurry! Go!
But...
水影を やったのか？
It's all over for me...
You don’t have to be
a Medic Ninja to know that, right?
いや まだ死んだわけじゃない。
じゃあ… ゴフッ！ 早く行け。
しかし…。
I’m sorry.
What a stupid thing to say.
Do you have any last words
for anyone?
俺が もうダメだってのは→
医療班でもない お前にだって
わかるだろうが。
Like I'd have anyone, idiot.
(イタチ)すまない。
バカ言うな。
誰かに何か伝えたいことがあれば
聞いておく。
I see... But you have someone
like that, huh?
ハッ バカ野郎。
Hurry and go!
そんなヤツ 誰もいねえよ。
I’m just gonna drop dead, right here,
where I'm from...
(十蔵)そうか。 お前には
そういうヤツが いるんだな。
... this god-forsaken,
Blood Mist Village...
I thought my only partner...
さっさと行け。
was this guy here, but...
俺は ただ この元いた場所で
くたばるだけだ。
(十蔵)この忌々しい血霧の里で。
俺の相棒は
こいつだけだと思っていたが…。
Juzo Biwa is dead.
Oh my, and he was
your teammate, Itachi.
The Jinchuriki of
the Three Tails killed him.
Which means you took on
the Mizukage and came out of it alive.
(ペイン)枇杷十蔵が やられた。
(大蛇丸)おや まあ
イタチ君と一緒だったというのに。
Another one of us is dead.
(イタチ)相手は 三尾の人柱力だった。
Rather than being killed by the enemy,
he was killed by friendly fire.
(大蛇丸)では イタチ君は 水影相手に
無事 戻ってきたってことね。
He was just too slow.
(ペイン)やられたのは もう１人いる。
Let everyone here be the judge of that.
(ゼツ)敵に やられたというよりは→
味方に やられたというところだ。
(角都)
あの野郎が グズグズしてただけだ。
Fire Style: Searing Migraine!
(ゼツ)その判断は 皆に任せる。
Done in bad faith.
Sounds like it was on purpose.
He should have just dodged it.
(角都)火遁 頭刻苦！
You ignored your partner, didn't you?
So what?
(ヒルコ)故意だな。
(大蛇丸)わざとね。
You wanted to kill him, didn't you?
(角都)かわせばいいだけの話だ。
So what?
Oh, nothing. It just seems
to happen a lot.
(大蛇丸)あなた 相棒をずいぶんと
疎んじてたでしょ。
The Akatsuki works in two-man teams.
それが なんだ？
殺したいと思ってたんじゃない？
What will you do, Kakuzu?
Will you team up with Itachi
who’s also lost his partner?
それが なんだ？
いいえ よくあることだから。
As long as he doesn’t irritate me.
(ペイン)暁は ツーマンセルで動く
どうする？ 角都。
I wouldn’t know how to cater
to your moods.
What the hell did you say?
Then let's team up and I'll show you.
相棒を失った者同士
イタチと組むか？
Wait, I’ll team up with Itachi.
(角都)コイツが 俺を
イラつかせなきゃ それでいい。
Are you trying to make a fool out of me?!
(イタチ)俺は アンタの
ご機嫌の取り方を知らない。
なんだとテメエ
じゃあ 組んで教えてやろう。
The Akatsuki needs to
find some new members.
(大蛇丸)待って。
イタチ君とは 私が組むわ。
We’ll put this issue on hold until we do.
(ヒルコ)テメエ 俺をコケにする気か。
(ペイン)暁には 新しいメンバーが必要だ。
そのときまで
この件は保留にする。
Do you know what eternal life is, Itachi?
I don’t know yet, either.
うっ…。
That’s why I need a new body.
(大蛇丸)永遠の命って
何かわかる？ イタチ君。
A magnificent body to link me
to eternal life.
うっ…。
First of all, the problem with you...
is your greed.
私にも まだわからない。
だから 新しい肉体がいるの。
Impossible! Have I fallen prey to
the Paralysis Jutsu?
永遠に連なる すばらしい肉体が。
それは しょせん
お前の欲の問題だ。
What incredible Visual Prowess...
まさか この私が金縛りの術に…。
Magnificent!
なんという瞳力 すばらしい…。
Orochimaru...
Try all of the jutsu you wish...
But, my eyes can see through
all of them.
うっ うぅ…。
You're so blunt...
I’m not sure what to do with you.
大蛇丸… お前のいかなる術も→
Whether to kill you right now,
or find a way to use you.
この眼の前では
何の効力も持たない。
言ってくれるじゃないの。
I-Itachi!
You just don’t have enough...
俺は アンタを どうすればいいのか
わからない。
ここで このまま殺せばいいのか。
あるいは 何か使い道があるのか。
No, you lack it completely... the greed...
イタチ…。
お前には足りないのだ。
for human life!
いや 足り過ぎている。 欲望が。
Lord Orochimaru!
I’ll definitely get you back for this.
お前は 人の命を…。
(カブト)大蛇丸様！
(大蛇丸)この借りは
返すわよ 必ず。
Orochimaru betrayed and
deserted our organization.
I knew it, that bastard.
He always put himself
before the organization.
(ペイン)大蛇丸が
組織を裏切り 抜けていった。
I don’t intend to let Orochimaru
get away with this,
(ヒルコ)けっ！
あの野郎 やっぱりか。
but right now,
we’re short on members.
Hey! Hey! Hey!
組織よりも
自分のことを優先しやがった。
How about letting me join?
Get lost!
(ペイン)大蛇丸を このままに
しておくつもりはないが→
Okay...
Leave Orochimaru to me.
今は メンバーが足りない。
His subordinate, Kabuto, is my puppet.
(トビ)はい！ はい！ はい！
僕を入れては どうでしょう？
(ヒルコ)すっこんでろ。
(トビ)はい…。
I’ll find out where
he’s hiding out in no time.
大蛇丸のことは 俺に任せな。
No need to rush.
ヤツが 部下に使っている
カブトってのは→
I have someone in mind
to be your partner.
俺の傀儡人形みたいなもんだ。
It can wait until he joins us.
What about me?
すぐに隠れ場所をつかんでやる。
Do I team up with Itachi?
(ペイン)そう急ぐな。
お前の相棒の目星はつけている。
Work alone for a while longer.
I have someone else I’ve prepared
to partner up with Itachi.
ソイツを仲間に引き入れてからだ。
(角都)俺は どうする？
イタチと組むのか？
もう少し １人でいろ。
イタチには 別の相棒を用意してる。
I’m going to be your partner
from today.
(鬼鮫)今日から あなたと
組むことになった者です。
kaze ga fui te iku
The wind is blowing
yoru o mata yorokete aruku
I stagger through the night
butsukatte koron de shippai bakkashite
Colliding, falling, and failing
make sou ni naru kedo
I'm always about to lose
warawaretatte ii yo kanarazu umaku iku sa
Go ahead and laugh, I'll figure out a way
gomen ne datte ieru
I'm even willing to say I'm sorry
nakitai nakitai nakitai kurai ni
Until we feel like crying and crying
kirei na tsuki no shita uta o utaou
Let's sing a song under the pretty moonlight
donna ni kuradanai sekai datte ii yo
It doesn't matter how awful the world is
setsunai setsunai rarabai kurai ni
Like a sad, sad lullaby
mune ga kurushikute mo hecchara na no sa
even if it hurts inside, it won't bother us
naki sou naki sou naki sou na hodo
Until we're about to cry and cry
yasashii uta datte arun dakara
There will always be a gentle song
Hey, you over there!
I’m not gonna fall for
your genjutsu ever again, hmm!
I’m going to give you a little taste
of what art is.
Let's leave it at that.
Sasori...
partner with Deidara and
go kill Orochimaru.
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "Partner"
Who the hell is this Orochimaru guy?